Anna and the King is a drama, romance, history film directed by Andy Tennant.
The story of the romance between the King of Siam (now Thailand) and the
widowed British school teacher Anna Leonowens during the 1860s.
Anna teaches the children and becomes romanced by the King.
She convinces him that a man can be loved by just one woman.
Anna, played by Jodie Foster.
King Mongkut, played by Chow Yun-Fat.
Tuptim, played by Bai Ling.
Louis, played by Tom Felton.
The Kralahome, played by Syed Alwi.
General Alak, played by Randall Duk Kim.
Anna and the King is a 1999 American biographical
period drama film directed by Andy Tennant.
Steve Meerson and Peter Krikes loosely based their screenplay on the 1944 novel Anna and the King
of Siam, which gives a fictionalized account of the diaries of Anna Leonowens.
It stars Jodie Foster as Leonowens, an English school teacher in Siam during the late 19th century,
who becomes the teacher of King Mongkut's (Chow Yun-fat) many children and wives.
It was mostly shot in Malaysia, particularly in the
Penang, Ipoh and Langkawi regions.
Anna and the King was released in the United States on
December 17, 1999, by 20th Century Fox.
The film was subject to controversy when the Thai government deemed it historically inaccurate
and insulting to the royal family and banned its distribution in the country.
It received mixed reviews from critics who praised the production values, costume
design, and musical score but criticised its screenplay and length.
The film grossed $114 million worldwide, against its $92 million budget.
It received two nominations at the 72nd Academy Awards:
Best Art Direction and Best Costume Design.
The film explores themes of daughter, death penalty, civil
war, parent child relationship, traitor.
The tone is emotional.